RESUME

ALOK YADAV



B. TECH (Mechanical Engineering)

Contact Information:

Contact No.: -+918287248481,7827447644

Email: -

alokmechviet@gmail.com

Residential Address:

Indirapuram, Ghaziabad (U.P)

Pin code: 201014

Permanent Address:

Vill- Tilaura, Po-Pali

Sahjanwa, Gorakhpur (U.P)

Pin code :273209

Career Objective:

I intend to build a career with leading corporate of hi-tech environment with committed & dedicated people, which will help me to explore myself fully and realize my potential. I am willing to work as a key player in challenging and creative environment, to continuously upgrade and acquire knowledge and skills to effectively use in industry.

Working Experience:

1. Wistron Info COMM Manufacturing PVT. LTD.

Wistron is a Private Limited is Founded in 2001, is in Bangalore and manufacturers for Apple products and provide all electronics sector services. It is TPS and OEM and design provide in electronics industries

Client- Apple Inc

DESIGNATION: Sr. Industrial Engineer

DURATION: May 2022

2. TRANSSION HOLDINGS INDIA PVT. LTD.

Transsion Holdings India Private Limited is Founded in 2006, TRANSSION Holdings is committed to becoming consumers' favourite smart device, brand portfolio comprises its best known leading mobile phone brands in emerging markets, including Tecno, Itel and Infinix, Carlcare for after-sales services, Oraimo for smart accessories as well as Syinix for home appliances.

DESIGNATION: Sr. Industrial Engineer DURATION: Sept 2018 to Apr 2022.

3. OPPO MOBILE INDIA PVT. LTD.

OPPO MOBILE INDIA is a global electronics and technology service provider that delivers the latest and most exquisite mobile electronic devices in over 20 countries, including the United States, China, Australia and many countries throughout Europe, Southeast Asia, South Asia, the Middle East and Africa.

DESIGNATION: Engineer

DURATION: Sept 2016 to May 2018.

4. MOBASE INDIA PVT. LTD.

MOBASE INDIA is a global provider of high-Quality Mobile Accessories by its own technology and manufacturing facility in India. Since it was established in Jan-2014, we have been focusing on the development of unique technology.

CLIENT- Samsung India Electronics Ltd. DESIGNATION: PI Engineer (Assembly) DURATION: Dec 2014 to Sept 2016.

PERSONAL DATA:

Name: Alok Yadav

Date of Birth: 07th Oct 1993

Father Name: Rajendra Yadav

Gender: Male

Marital Status: Single

Languages Known: English &

Hindi

Nationality: Indian

Hobbies: Travelling, Cooking &

Reading.

Strengths: Work as a team leader, Positive attitude with hard work, Self-confidence, willing to learn new thing, Punctual & determined.

Brief Profile:

Experience of more than **7 years** as an Industrial Engineer in Mobile smartphone and feature phone Manufacturing sector in India. Having a strong technical and broad-based background with extensive knowledge of various Production, Process and Industrial engineering aspects gained while working with organizations engaged in the field of Mobile manufacturing. Offering commitment and interpersonal skill, willing to work anywhere in India.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Develop Coordinate & Monitor all aspects of product, including selection of assembly methods and operations.
- As a GET in Mobase India Pvt. Ltd. have knowledge of all department like **Plastic Injection molding, Coating, evaporation, case assembly and sub assembly**.
- Perform personnel functions, such as supervision of production method, time study, layout design, Jig and Fixture modification, prepare documents for process & design of evaluation programs.
- If any defect due to process and layout error, then give proper training of responsible department for improve Quality and skills of operators.
- Preparation of **layout** for **reduced cycle time** and effective utilization of resources.
- Implementation of suggestions and take part in **Cost saving activities**.
- Preparation & modification of Process control documents and **TIME STUDY**.
- Providing training and knowledge of each process to each operator and Production Engineer for best productivity.
- Evaluating information to determine compliance with standards.
- Maintain **Utilization report** and prepare daily utilization report and improvement report.
- Prepare **SOP**, **PROCESS FLOW CHART**, Consumable, Trays bumpers and **tools and fixtures required for production**.
- Analyzing manufacturing issues and **Ergonomic issue** with root cause and provide the corrective action and preventing action to close the issues.
- Prepare **POR**, as per POR control the manpower utilizations, manpower **planning of contract, ODLs and IDLs** and saved the cost of manpower.

Work Area:

- Mobile rear housing, front housing, bracket, battery cover injection coating evaporation.
- Laser cutting of rear housing & battery cover.
- Mobile part case assembly and sub assembly.
- Feature-phone assembly, testing & packing.
- Smart-phone assembly, testing, aging & packing.

Key Skills:

- Sufficient knowledge & understanding of business processes and skills in Production and Process Improvement by analyzing improvement opportunities, planning & implementing actions required and monitoring system effectiveness.
- Decide strategy for productivity improvement, monitor & improve productivity with proper managing of all resources (Manpower / Machine / Material/Method/ Environment).
- Knowledge about 6S, IE TOOLS, QUALITY TOOLS, KAI-ZEN, 8W, OEE, SMED, LOB, Six sigma, Lean manufacturing basics tools and MOST theory.
- Knowledge about product design process, assembly method process, selection of **JIGs and tools** and coast saving activity.
- Working knowledge of MS-EXCEL, PowerPoint, MES and Autocad.

Personal Skills:

- 1. Good analytical and logical skills.
- 2. Proficient Problem-solving capacity.
- 3. Can work independently.
- 4. Good communication and interpersonal skills.
- 5. Highly motivated to work as a team.

Technical Qualifications:

Graduation: -

Examination Passed	University	Year of passing	Percen tage
B.Tech.(Mechanical	U.P. Technical	2014	72 %
Engineering)	University,		
	Lucknow, U.P.		

Academic Qualification:

Examination Passed	Name of the Board	Year of passing	Percentage
Senior Secondary School	U.P.BOARD	2009	66
Secondary School	U.P.BOARD	2007	73

Achievements:

- ➤ Participate in Initial setup of **SAMSUNG** models line like-**SM-J200F**, **SM-B350E**, **SM-Z300H**, **SM-J210F**.
- ➤ Participate in Initial setup of some model's line in **OPPO** like-**F1S**, **A37**, **A71L**, **1PLUS 5**, **1 PLUS 5T AND 1 PLUS 6T**.
- ➤ Participate in Initial setup of some model's line in **Transsion** like-**Itel features phone**, **Tecno smartphones and Infinix smartphones**.

Project (B. Tech.):

Successful completion of **ELECTRO MAGNETIC BRAKING SYSTEM** Under my Guidance and Leadership.

Declaration:

I consider myself familiar with mechanical Engineering aspects. I am also confident of my ability to work in a team.

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge.

Place:	
Date:	Signature